Nearly all applications have a need to store data so that it can be accessed later.
تحتاج جميع التطبيقات تقريبًا إلى تخزين البيانات بحيث يمكن الوصول إليها لاحقًا.
Let's use Twitter as an example.
دعونا نستخدم Twitter كمثال.
Every time I write a tweet,
في كل مرة أكتب فيها تغريدة،
the text of my tweet needs to be stored somewhere so that all my followers can read it.
فإن نص التغريدة يلزم تخزينه في مكان ما حتى يتمكن كل المتابعين من قراءته.
Twitter stores a bunch of information about my tweet.
يخزن Twitter مجموعة كاملة من المعلومات عن تغريدتي.
Who the author is?
من المؤلف؟
Me. The time I wrote it,
أنا. الوقت الذي كتبت فيه التغريدة،
links to any other relevant tweets if I'm writing a reply or a re-tweet, etcetera.
روابط لأى تغريدات أخرى ذات صلة إذا كنت أكتب ردًا أو إعادة نشر تغريدة، إلى آخره.
All this information is used to determine who sees my tweet and when they see it.
كل هذه المعلومات تستخدم لتحديد من يرى تغريدتي ومتى يرونها.
This is the function databases serve.
هذه هي دالة databases serve.
They store information so that it can be accessed later,
يقومون بتخزين المعلومات، بحيث يمكن الوصول إليها لاحقًا،
and SQL is the language that allows analysts and others to access that information.
وSQL هي اللغة التي تمكن المحلل والآخرين من الوصول إلى هذه المعلومات.
Databases have a number of attributes that make them great for this.
تتميز قواعد البيانات بمجوعة من السمات التي تجعلها رائعة لهذا الغرض.
Most importantly, databases do a lot to check for data integrity.
والأهم من ذلك، أن قواعد البيانات تقوم بالكثير للتحقق من مصداقية البيانات.
They can make sure that the data entered is consistent.
يمكنها التأكد من أن البيانات المدخلة متسقة.
For example, if you're storing the number of children a given person has,
على سبيل المثال، إذا كنت تخزن عدد الأطفال لدى شخص معين،
the database can enforce that only whole numbers be used,
يمكن لقاعدة البيانات أن تفرض استخدام الأعداد الصحيحة فقط،
since you can't have half a child.
حيث إنه لا يمكن أن يكون لديك نصف طفل.
Databases are also really fast,
قواعد البيانات سريعة جدًا حقًا،
they can perform operations very quickly across
يمكنها إجراء العمليات بسرعة على
very large data sets and can be optimized for extra speed.
مجموعة بيانات كبيرة ويمكن تحسينها لزيادة السرعة.
Databases are shared entities.
قواعد البيانات عبارة عن كيانات مشتركة.
Many people can access a database concurrently.
يمكن للكثير من الأشخاص الدخول إلى قاعدة البيانات في نفس الوقت.
More importantly, all of those people will be working with the same data.
والأهم من ذلك، أن كل هؤلاء الأشخاص سيعملون مع نفس المعلومات.
To facilitate this, databases have lots of administrative features like access controls.
لنسهل الأمر، قواعد البيانات لديها العديد من المميزات الإدارية مثل التحكم في الوصول.